Skillful Software Architect with 15 years designing development frameworks and guidelines to expedite and enhance application engineering. Versed in numerous software categories for business and private users. Adept at constructing software architecture suited to rapid deployment across multiple projects to reduce development times and costs.

## **Work History**

2014-03 -Current

## **Principal Architect**

FINRA, Rockville, MD

- Designed and next generation data collection services to support yearly intake of 5 million fillings per year.
- Designed Microservice to support onboarding data collection template and data up to 5000 per day
- Designed platform to incorporate machine learning to detect 20 different types of Personal Identifiable Information (PII) in 50,000 incoming transactions per day.

2010-07 -2014-03

## **Sr Software Engineer**

Dawn Technologies, Detroit, Lansing, Rockville, Michigan

- As consultant worked on-site at different client locations providing services of designing and developing solutions
- Designed and developed Solar Wind land Easement management system at Detroit Energy (DTE) to support 50,000 acres of easement and payments associated with it for every quarter
- Maintained Curian capital managed investment portfolio system at Jackson National Life Insurance supporting 1 million customers.

2005-03 -2010-07

## **Software Engineer**

Tech Mahindra, San Ramon, CA

- As consultant worked on-site at AT&T to support services to develop ordering system for AT&T to support daily ordering volume of 100 thousand Wireline products per day in all markets.
- Established Rules Engine and Ordering System for AT&T to support 250 different product combinations and their configurations

## **Education**

2001-10 -

## **MS: Information Systems**

2003-07

Kakatiya University - India

Artificial Intelligence, Mobile Communications; Cryptography and Network

Security, Information

1998-10 -2001-07

## **BS: Computer Applications**

Kakativa University - India

Operating Systems, Databases, Algorithms, Programming Languages, Computer Architecture, Computer Networks, System Analysis and Design

## Certifications

2017-06

AWS Certified Associate Solution Architect

2005-02

Sun Certified Java Programmer

## **Open Source work**

- Created 2 open source chrome plugins
- Created Dart package for generating random dates
- Contributed to Everit Json Schema project
- Created Eclipse plugin

# Naveen Gurram

Software Architect

### Contact

### **Address**

Clarksburg, United States, 20871

### Phone

925-699-5376

### E-mail

gurram.naveen@gmail.com

### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/naveengurram/

### www

https://www.naveengurram.com

## **Skills**

AWS

**REST** 

GraphQL

Frontend

**AWS** 

Machine Learning

Microservices

NoSQL

Agile

SOA

Search solutions

Message driven architecture